Evan Patrick

Overview:

I am a rapid applications developer in the Mendix platform. With prior experience with JavaScript, Python Django, HTML and CSS. I have certifications in JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. Prior to working in application development, I had extensive experience in research and development environments. Working



on multiple research teams during his undergrad, as well as in many extracurricular engineering groups. I am currently trying to expand my knowledge and break into more in depth and exciting software engineering roles.

Work Experience:

EPI-USE America, Inc | Rapid Application Developer October 2021 - Present

- Develops Enterprise level applications for clients of EPI-USE America Inc
- Works across many platforms and technologies to ensure data access
- Works in both Agile or Waterfall environments depending on client needs
- Communicates with product owner over business needs of the application
- Trains client employees on use of new software
- Manages merging and deployment of applications via CI/CD environments
- Documents best practices for team members

Education & Certifications:

University of Tennessee Graduated May 2019 BS Chemical Engineering GPA 3.5

https://www.theodinproject.com/dashboard

The Odin Project, JavaScript Foundations 2019 -2020 The Odin Project, JavaScript Full Stack Development 2020 – Present

https://academy.mendix.com/link/home

Mendix, Rapid Application Developer, Rapid Application Certified

Cell 423-240-0023 EvanPatrick3@protonmail.com

Portfolio Website:

https://www.evanpatrick.site/

Github:

https://github.com/EvanPatrick423

Technical Skills:

- JavaScript
 - o node.is
 - express
- Python
 - o Django
- Mendix
- Jenkins CI/CD tool
- PostgreSQL
- CSS
- HTML5
- VBA
- Labview
- ChemCad
- Solidworks
- Proficient in Office

Activities:

Chem-E-Car Captain

Chemical Engineering Competition

August 2016 - December 2018

- AIChE Nationals 2018 placed 8th
- AIChE Nationals 2017 placed 13th
- AIChE Regionals 2017 placed 3rd

Oki Turbo

November 2016 - Present

 We create, refine, memorize, perform, and record pieces of music

Work Experience: (cont)

Chattanooga Coin | Systems Administrator February 2021 – October 2021

- Managed the website chattanoogacoins.com
 - Updated site with new products
 - Designed the look and structure of the site
 - Developed software for businesses needs
- Designed and published new catalogs
- Solves problems with any IT related issues

Legacy Box | Repair and IT Technician February 2020 – February 2021

- Managed the operations of 37 media capture stations
- Troubleshot stations, media capturing software and media printers
- Created Routine Maintenance Schedules to prevent and reduce downtime on stations
- Performed routine maintenance on all media capture stations
- Improved the working efficiency of the floor through continuous improvement practices

Vital Farms | Head of R&D/Laboratory Manager September 2019 – February 2020

- Designed a centrifugal partition chromatography (CPC) process for extraction of cannabinoid compounds, a method of extraction that achieves higher extraction purity, with lower operational cost
- Researched and found manufacturers of CPC equipment that meet the companies standard for CBD oil extraction and separation processes
- Worked with the regional manager and CEO to source buyers, harvest, process, and store the physical biomass, and renovate our extraction laboratory

University of Tennessee | Research Assistant, Dr. Harris May 2019 – August 2019

- Designed network communication structure using Labview, that would allow researchers to operate the chemical engineering controls systems lab machines remotely from any internet capable devices.
- Researched microcontrollers that meet requirements of communication software.

Activities: (cont)

Tau Beta Pi Engineering Honors Society

Community Service Leader November 2018 - Present

- Collaborated in small teams to organize community service events.
 Ours was to try to get high school students excited about engineering and engineering concepts.
- To help achieve this I was the main point of contact between our group and a local teacher wanting to make rudimentary electric guitars as a project for their high school, while also helping the teacher figure out how to achieve said goal and implement for class room.

Honors:

Graduated University of Tennessee with Deans list distinction for high academic standing 2015 – 2019

Tau Beta Pi Engineering Honors Society Member